AMMAR ABBKAR

Atlanta, GA 6785592765 abbkarammar107@gmail.com

An Computer Science major with a record reflecting outstanding academic achievement while maintaining a high level of success in extracurricular activities. My work history includes working in Fin-Tech, software, hardware, sales, teaching, and electronics lab experience where leadership, supervision, critical thinking, and collaborative teamwork skills were utilized. Fluent in both English and Arabic.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst

2019 to Present

Amazon

Duluth, GA

- Worked on the Payment Express Implementation team to improve internal work management by researching, developing, and integrating new tools and processes.
- · Tested and provided feedback on lab projects using Spark, Scala, Linux.
- Analyzed users needs and came up with design software solutions.
- Provided support, enhancement and maintenance to new and existing projects.

Lab Technician Assistant

2019 to 2019

Georgia State University

Atlanta, GA

- Instructed underprivileged high school students and led tutorial sessions for groups of up to 20 students on engineering concepts, such as circuit analysis and computational logic circuits. Also used AutoCAD and SolidWorks for design projects
- Supervised workshops focusing on robotics, where students would build and program a Parallax Activity Bot. Also designed electrical circuits using a microcontroller.

SKILLS

MySQL	
Git	
PLC	
Python	
HTML	
Hadoop	
Scala	
Spark	
Linux	
AutoCAD	
AWS	
Data Lake	
Azure	
Cloud services	

Java

C++

Jenkins

Java scripts

EDUCATION

Georgia State University

Bachelor's Computer Science Atlanta, GA 2019 to Present